#### **Derrick Holleman**

## **Full Stack Software Engineer**

Minneapolis, MN | (612) 418-5274 | derrickholleman@gmail.com

Portfolio Website | GitHub | LinkedIn

Full stack software engineer with a love for problem solving and collaborating with a team. Great eye for detail and enjoys developing applications that are high quality and user-friendly. Background as a freelance web developer built up valuable experience working with clients and using a variety of different technologies.

#### SKILLS

HTML | CSS | Javascript | React | Bootstrap | Tailwind CSS | Node.js | Express.js | Knex.js | PostgreSQL | MongoDB | Git | Heroku | Netlify | Unit Testing | Mocha | Chai.js | React Testing Library | RESTful APIs | NPM | JSON Web Tokens | Docker | Agile Development

### **PROJECTS**

Blackjack Game | Javascript, CSS, HTML. Hosted on Netlify

Live | GitHub Repo

- Developed a blackjack game to test the player's luck against a random number generator. The player can choose a custom username and is prompted to start a new game after going below 0 points.
- Implemented code with complex logic while neatly keeping track of data through readable functions.
- Created responsive styling from scratch using CSS.

Flash Cards App | React, JSON server, Bootstrap, Docker

Live | Front-end | Back-end

- Designed a flash cards app with full CRUD functionality to help users stay organized and study.
- Configured a Docker file so that the project can be run in any development environment.
- Hosted the client on Vercel and the server on Heroku as a workaround for the JSON-server API.

Hatchways Filter Challenge | React, CSS. Hosted on Netlify

Live | GitHub Repo

- Created a scrollable card in which student data is fetched from an API and made into a list.
- Students can have tags added to them and the list can be filtered by full name and/or tag.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Freelance Web Developer

Self-employed

Minneapolis, MN

mployed March 2021 - Present

- Developed applications and designed web pages for clients to fit their requirements.
- Contributed to open source projects, some used by thousands of users.
- Worked with a variety of front-end technologies depending on the needs of the project.

**Maintenance Associate** 

SuperValu

Brooklyn Park, MN

June 2014 - December 2019

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Certificate, Software Engineering**

Remote

Thinkful

September 2021 - January 2022

- Designed mobile-first full-stack applications from conception to deployment.
- Learned industry best practices during lectures with working software engineers.
- Collaborated with fellow students daily and mentored students who were struggling in the course.

Bachelor of Arts, Music Performance Augsburg University Minneapolis, MN January 2018 - May 2019

Music Performance St. Paul, MN McNally Smith College of Music (school closed December 2017) September 2014 - December 2017